He took o Rommel...the Sahara...and a unit of
untrained me to blow the Desert Fox to Hell.
Raid on Rommel is a war, action film directed by Henry Hathaway.
Captain Foster plans on raiding German-occupied Tobruk with hand- picked commandos, but a
mixup leaves him with a medical unit led by a Quaker conscientious objector.
Capt. Alex Foster, played by Richard Burton.
Sgt. Maj. Allan MacKenzie, played by John Colicos.
Gen. Erwin Rommel, played by Wolfgang Preiss.
Maj. Hugh Tarkington, played by Clinton Greyn.
Vivianne Gagliardo, played by Danielle De Metz.
Schroeder, played by Karl-Otto Alberty.
Raid on Rommel is a 1971 American war film directed by Henry Hathaway and starring Richard
Burton, John Colicos, Clinton Greyn, Danielle De Metz and Wolfgang Preiss.
The film centers on a British commando attempting to
destroy German gun emplacements in Tobruk.
Originally intended as a made-for-television film, Raid on Rommel extensively reuses
action footage from 1967's Tobruk, and the storyline is also largely the same.
The film was released by Universal Pictures on February 12, 1971,
and was both a critical and commercial failure.
The film explores themes of world war ii,
commando, desert, libyan desert, rommel.